what up scobie's like I caught shirt on
today let's wait for a few people
so while we wait for some people to get
in here I'm gonna flip you guys to the
other cab
and to show you my brand new desk Oh
does a localizer work well we're on the
periscope talking this goes but my new
desk look it's a standing desk you know
I'm even gonna put my phone back in
color
oh cool okay but yeah I mean we're
partially here to shelter the new desk
and the new beautiful office no I don't
really stand there's no way I'm actually
gonna use the standing desk I'm honest
do I play PC games you I play Age of
Empires 2 and a play super smash bros
that's my plan
yeah we got a play we got a play man um
but yeah so check out this is the
internal shop kamidana Y shop that
internal dah dah dah dah
check out those handles the Aeons a
couple of pause if you go pronouns we
got Wi-Fi modules we've got a common a
sovereignty rawr some pedals for some
cars so the one on the left is a honda
pedal and the one on the right is a
toyota pedal who is disappointed by the
toyota pedal look at it it's kind of
disappointing
how much hardware products is too much
when you have enough hardware to make
your car well to make driving better and
that's really what we're here to talk
about tonight greenish tint to my camera
so the white balance isn't working well
yeah we just everyone got one hundred
dollars to improve their desk they can
even spend it on tchotchkes like Babe
Ruth bobbleheads that's ok that's ok
we have this is a this is the this is
the ECU that I bricked in the Toyota my
own brick the one that's in there but I
bought a spare one ok let's get to the
main top
how can driving be better this is really
we're gonna try to have a conversation
on periscope I don't know if this is
gonna work but the two things that I
think
when I think about driving I think about
it's a lot of boredom interspersed with
a few moments of stress so maybe you can
focus on these two is like kind of
different regimes you want to alleviate
the boredom and you want to I think we
really want to do about the stress part
is you want to alert in advance right
things are a lot less stressful if you
know you're gonna get an alert
beforehand that something's about about
to happen
right the real the real thing that keeps
you on the edge and kind of what anxiety
itself is is a fear of me but fear of
kind of the unknown like you know that
you might have to do something but
you're not exactly sure what OH
fear is like oh I'm afraid literally
that there might be you know a mugger
down that alley right you're actually
afraid of something anxiety is you're
just walking down the street and
something feels a little bit awful right
so so stress stress and then and well
anxiety leads to stress right so how can
drive will be better we have to work on
alleviating boredom and alleviating
stress gamification I wonder about that
I wonder if that's the idea if you want
a game of I like maybe it makes it more
exciting
okay well we'll add glad that as an idea
like how can we make driving more
exciting is that what we want to do in
the first place right like there's kind
of two paths maybe you can take you guys
read alex wyse article about like the
human driving rights manifesto a lot of
it was kind of it but um well games
caused stress but I don't think they
caused anxieties all right um so so you
know this stress leads to anxiety and
this is a big problem in the modern
world and really what we want to
eliminate right dopamine release when
uncertain rewards yeah I mean it's kind
of true and that's kind
that's kind of sketchy I'm sick of
wasting my time driving I mean yeah that
comes really back to the boredom factor
right but the idea that driving is a
waste of time really has to do with
boredom so I don't know I mean I don't
know about about about more exciting and
I shouldn't put a line to anxiety
because we haven't eliminated it yeah so
we will erase the line and we will come
back up and ah yeah okay yeah did you
guys like the last periscope by the way
that we had an actual like the rest of
the phone up against something so people
could people could see best feel about
that but okay so boredom people want to
drive less hello just just now this is
this is the there's lots of like this is
scenarios that are particularly boring
on long drives in the highway when
you're not doing much remember like this
was great okay um yeah okay I mean I you
guys probably can't see the board
anything for periscope yeah the front
camera okay you guys like the front
camera we can we can we can go here a
life swings like a pendulum backward and
forward between pain and boredom um okay
so how can driving be better we want to
people like the rant ones more the rant
ones get a lot more views this isn't a
rant this is talking about improving the
world people um now see this is hard to
do like you can see me now but it's hard
for me to hold the phone out here okay
let's go
so so so let's do you guys agree that
they're so bored I'm gonna fix for bored
maybe we'll do it like that like a fix
for boredom would be to make driving
more exciting and a fix for stress and
anxiety is basically reliable alerting
if you know I mean you might become
anxious about the alert but that has
more to do with how the alert is
designed but if the alert is like
something terrible might happen in ten
minutes and of course you're gonna have
a stressful ten minutes right but if the
alert is you know literally in 15
seconds you know that guy's looks like
he's coming in too fast
just make sure you hit the brakes you do
this nobody tells you exactly what to do
and you're good about that right this is
obviously well before we get to level
four or five because you know that stuff
is mostly it's mostly figures most cars
not it's not safer than people right
it's not and they cheaper than people
but it's not safe taking people plan
exchange responsibility of driving a I
drive for easy parts only make it
commitment I don't really know what that
means so well the other solution is the
other solution instead of more exciting
to the boarding problem is something
else right like what if people could
just do something else
way in a solution to stress and anxiety
is reliable learning so now what would
it take well okay so more exciting can
just get worked on while driving right
so so maybe maybe um you know this is
more exciting you can do easily with
level two
alright you don't need you just want to
make something more exciting you can you
can share ways and that's effectively
you think of ways driving a system right
we don't think of ourselves is really
that different from from ways yeah naps
fall in the realm of something else
so that would be level three level three
is you know when the car gives you
enough of
warning to my waking up for a nap is
kind of odd it's kind of yeah Charlotte
energy for getting cam reported that's
awesome if it's done wait but how'd you
do that I flipped the camera I think
there's a bounty for that one right that
one doesn't ever do yes you if someone
managed to get one of the undie SVSU
Lascars working will do what we'll do
about it um but yeah so reliable
alerting depends how reliable well just
lateral okay reliable alerting is is l2
and l3 and l4 depending on how reliable
you want like I Section l3 is already
full reliability ml4 would actually be
able to do the scenario for you maybe
yeah if you want alerting its l2 if you
want reliable it sounds great still
using stock SEC okay so this isn't a
lateral Woodstock X you see that's
pretty cool think the longitudinals is
the hard part but yeah ok so how can
drive can be better we want to do am I
missing something on like the bad column
some roads are l2 some roads never l4 am
I missing V like maybe you know we'll
divide this I just got new markers which
I'm really excited about what gonna have
like all the colors of the marker
spectrum come so that is very exciting
okay maybe over here on this side we'll
put the problem and over here on this
side we'll put the solution will there
be alerts when the lanes are detected no
lanes are gonna go away lanes are stupid
well there be alerts when it's not
confident yeah there should be there
should be and we can we can work on that
kind of stuff but yeah so I'm missing
anything in my in my texana me
but what's what else is wrong with
dragon
think about the city you're constantly
I'm to pay attention to
and different things or you think about
driving on the highway and just you know
the crushing the crushing boredom of
that suggestions people suggestions
people other drivers problem is other
drivers well I mean I don't think other
drivers call his boredom I think I think
other drivers fall into the stress and
anxiety category right you're stressed
or anxious about what other people are
going to do goober driver's attention
divided your inability to be otherwise
productive so that's that's that's a
bordo thing right that's that's that's
the boredom problem with driving always
other drivers you know other drivers are
terrible I mean you know people might
breakdown problems like people talk
about this like in in politics you know
there's three types of solutions there's
solutions that need feudal buy-in
there's solutions that need many to buy
in and solutions that need everyone to
buy in the former are likely to happen
the second are unlikely to happen and
the last is completely impossible you'll
never ever get any everyone to buy and
you'll always get two factors so I don't
know what we can really do about other
drivers right put it over there into
problems I mean you know you can have
like stupid crap like I like you know
maybe next hour I'll say like oh well
you know we're gonna build up a database
of drivers and the other thing will
alert you when other bad drivers are in
the area I don't know about that like
it's just not gonna be it's not gonna be
it's not gonna be good detours
construction well is that problem your
potholes actually that's a good one
that's a good one what potholes and
stuff fall into is the problem is like
the physical motion of the vehicle right
and bumpiness and that's fixable through
a lot of electronic solutions potholes
is comfort yeah like motion bumpiness
comfort of other drivers and traffic
again the problem would even like really
thinking about that is that's not
solutions that you
that you can individually build and
anything that requires buy-in from a lot
or everyone is absolutely impossible um
so I think that we're just gonna strike
that one off the list because I mean
here's the thing right there's a certain
symmetry and other drivers which is you
know everyone hates other drivers but
you are an other driver scope what you
look at I'm not sure what that means but
but this can be this can be fixed right
so this can be fixed with better
controls this can be fixed with active
suspension and there's part of doing it
I think that may Bach has this like dual
camera system that's supposedly reading
the road I don't know if that works
field of view of human versus machine so
field of view is not like field of view
as a problem was driving oh it's a
prominent specific implementations of
driving you guys like you know the field
of view is it's a really easy game to
fix just stick more cameras on the car
notice how Tesla has solved the field of
view problem yet autopilot is still
about as good as all the pilot it's not
the problem isn't more cameras not be
the solution
sorry not the solutions not more cameras
but like field of view is not really a
problem but yeah the motion bumpiness in
comfort that's that's a good one that's
a good one you can literally make the
car experience better we can do this by
braking better we can do this by you
know if you're localized well enough you
can avoid potholes you can like have a
database you can know exactly where the
potholes are you can active detect right
um I mean think about it if you guys
have gone skiing you know you always
head for the smooth snow right so you
can detect smooth road that's that's an
interesting it's an interesting like
Aust you can put into
driving an optimizer why you're having
trouble spending $100 you're at 60 do
you find a lot of tchotchkes identify
potholes notify the city again I really
couldn't care less about like you know
fixing the problem like that
I think identify pothole drive around
poeple that's what humans do but what if
you did that every time and what if like
you could like drive around micro
potholes and stuff - well I'm gonna I'm
gonna talk to the city oh I'm gonna like
oh you I'm gonna talk to the DSF man
this sucks what sucks this periscope
sorry you don't have to watch
gosh beautify the videos they're pretty
fun because the question mean what else
what else
I liked the motion bulkiness comfort
yeah that's a problem with driving right
so what else what else
how can driving be better that's the
question it's at the top a little bit
washed out by the lights what are we
doing here well you know I mean
everybody saw the gem zero hardware
every downloaded in Vegas everybody's
noise cancellation I like that one
drinks that's a that's a that's a wait
wait sorry what was what was that before
what was the one I liked before drinks
first of all just let me scroll up
I liked that waste less fuel okay okay
cost
yeah in general people are willing to
trade off cost for convenience almost
always so I'm not sure how much can
really be done now what was the one I
liked forget it I was gonna write it who
said it yeah but what are we doing here
so save gas yeah yeah cost like yeah you
could say save gas I mean all right
again no one really cares about the
environment
some people will signal that they care
about the environment or you get water
at the restaurant I'm saving the job
ability to pee in the car noise Oh noise
yeah I mean noise cut probably falls
into the motion bumpiness and comfort
kind of wine um so apparently like the
Acura has has AMC stuff um like Oh
drinks without making a mess yeah that
falls under motion lumpiness comfort of
give AI personality nobody wants that um
keeping sensor clear and bad weather I
mean this autumn with drive it that's a
problem that's an implementation problem
the question we're asking here is how
can driving be better distance distance
that's an interesting one I mean
actually you know that's a good one if'n
it distance and you don't care about
distance you care about time if we could
figure out how to get people time back
so they spend less time in the car
that's good
um a lot of nav systems are trying to do
that but they're not good I like that
one I like that one accident avoidance
yeah I mean that's that falls on there
that falls under stress anxiety
anticipate stoplights yeah again stress
anxiety make driving easier I mean what
do you mean by it make driving easier
right like what's hard about it what are
the problems problem is it takes time
promise cost money the problem is that
the the ride is uncomfortable the
problem is parts of it are stressful the
problem is parts of it are boring really
speed limit again again the last thing I
ever want to do with my life is ask
government for anything so what will
never work to raise speed limits I don't
know I don't know why the speed limits
are what they are I don't really know
who sets them I don't know if it's uh
keep me in a better lane not behind this
yeah yeah I thought that falls into like
that is something right and that is
something it's similar to motion Comfort
bumpiness noise but some of those are
more characteristics of the car maybe
maybe we'll call that one skill all
right like on the skilled drivers you
know the kind of person who like slams
the brakes and sell your driving day
that's not for sale gross auto drive
though we're save on insurance cost yeah
I'll put that under cost save gas here's
generally how I feel about cost savings
they'll like I don't think that that
very often drives the calculus of many
things the number one thing that makes
people do something more is if it's more
convenient right everyone is like you
start up stuff you gotta you gotta think
this way push bad drivers off the road
um what's the question the question is
how can driving me better um yes a skill
and you know I think skill is kind of
what you're getting at with the you know
you want to not stay behind like a bad
driver
I oughta react to stock cars yeah these
are these are implementation things
right don't worry about that think about
the high level problem of how can
driving be better or maybe maybe I'll
phrase it a different way
what's bad about driving keep driver
engaged why is that a problem
like is that is that something bad about
driving it costs it gas insurance do all
those things could use less time I mean
this is really like you know magic novel
called maybe that's what we'll call
magic nap maybe that is what we'll build
with all of our naps
um driving involves attention yeah
probably involves attention I mean that
and that's that that's the boredom
problem right you fall asleep while
driving and then yeah this movies on the
display yeah I mean it all falls under
this something else category
he's getting a call I'm too many
unwanted updates and no options for
customization yeah you rather not be
engaged yeah rather my babies I don't
know what unwanted updates two cars to
open pilots customization is not
something people really want like people
might say they want customization but in
general like the only reason people want
customization the only people people who
reason people jailbroke their iPhones I
mean there was a piracy reason but it
really wasn't piracy in the beginning
and now you can still pirate and almost
nobody jailbreaks it's because it was
missing features right like there were
key features missing from the iPhone
that you had to jailbreak for since
mechanical problems before they happen
okay breakdowns yeah yeah we can we can
put that we can put that like
reliability breakdown kind of stuff
bility breakdown I don't know if I can
really call that driving though right
because that's once you're off the road
but yeah I guess it improves the whole
car experience I could care less about
remembering the positions of my seats
and my preferences music yeah I mean
honestly universe is that now you
want universal basic jobs you don't want
universal basic income you gotta do
people jobs people need something to do
you want to make money you gotta do
something right
Universal basica anticipatory
understanding yeah I mean that's to
reduce stress and anxiety so maybe we'll
put that as like it's not just reliable
alerting but it's like I mean alerting
is maybe too strong with a word reliable
communication is maybe the key here a
communication with the car yeah exactly
that safety dris right okay no one's
hacking your car over the Internet
that's fake news don't read the media
people get stupid things in their mind
right v2v these dumb in a minute like do
you guys are actually problems let me
tell you in my life I had to swerve to
avoid gear and I slid on ice these are
real problems I've experienced them
let's see my cars never hacked been
hacked and I don't know anyone was
positive attack I know tons of people
who get here and crash cuz right so
those are real problems I mean that's
you can tell something like no it's hot
it's hard in today's world oh god
massive massive amounts of information
so like v2v is not um I'm not
understanding any of these requiring V
to be dissolve right V to V are you know
we talked about how the EON already has
me to be you know it looks at the brake
lights of a problem pedestrians are a
problem I mean pedestrians are a problem
in the same way other drivers are a
problem so we'll add another crossed out
one on cyclist nobody likes cyclists man
it doesn't matter where you're
pedestrian or and no one like no
cyclists over V to be chat of passengers
you have this froze it's called text
messaging everyone does it while they
drive they shouldn't but they do what
can you do it's convenient all right
keyless is a problem you could keyless
actually stolen once yeah this B
interface I mean the interface is bad
yeah yeah we'll add that yeah I'm bad
interface uh so does it go under any of
these no no I don't think so but like
yeah bad interface I totally agree with
that we can we didn't we can we can fix
them what else what else we go what else
yoga while driving and they all fall
under the something else category the
border I don't care what you do you know
people who think about self-driving cars
will think about stuff like oh well you
know we should figure out what the
driver should do when they're not
driving what they're gonna use their
phone bro what are they doing they have
a minute to sit there what are people do
on the train whatever but yeah exactly
drinking and driving of course of course
that's what people want to do right just
will get a train whatever people do on a
train is exactly
I don't get like the link it's gonna be
new yeah massage seats you can buy a car
with massage sheets just don't be poor
in car bar yeah these aren't like okay
fine you know it has bars in it trains
mark them up yeah this always a good
idea
yeah hold up a lot of stuff yeah and I'm
gonna put this I'm gonna put this on our
wiki under internal wiki afterward after
GPS in vehicle sensors yeah yeah there's
a whole lot of ways to mitigate sliding
on ice I mean in some ways like ice is
already dealt with if you guys have used
a modern traction control system it's
super good at dealing with this and like
deer probably already dealt with by a be
a by sorry uh emergency AE be hard to
keep straight um so there are like
pretty good solutions for those and like
honestly those things have I feel I've
never been in the car during a navy-blue
the cut blade divert for tragic control
and I sort of wonder how people you know
did you go off the road in some
scenarios before it gamification yeah it
falls on to the boredom problem like
make driving more exciting no like
you're not going to be able to compete
with candy crush right so why not just
let people play candy crush that's
probably the better way to deal with the
gamification day right you know you know
augmented reality game for driving and
then let somebody else you don't put
this way letting Niantic build the
driving game once this driving car
reduces make dragon great again
I don't think driving was ever great I
think driving is better than it ever was
right now what'd you think of IPAs I
don't know what am i a sis it's not like
a pacemaker
meant by Napa I paced pretty nice got a
pacemaker
okay guys the board is pretty full we're
almost at 30 minutes thank you for
joining make sure to hit that subscribe
button
legalize go karts you should Lobby your
local people Jaguar do you mean the
animal
car you get a new car stop being poor
you know something we always say , steer
him yeah yeah yeah we'll start with the
comma pedal comma petals in good
progress but um yep yep yep electro
electronic tolls I mean again the
problem with electronic tolls is yeah
that would make it better but it
requires government's building new
models models are a mouthful comment
thank you for joining me how can drive
you to be better
periscope old cars with the steering
eject button okay okay okay okay
spared a future I bet they have one of
those got an eject button in your car
okay make sure to hit that subscribe
button thanks for joining comma army